Download movie subtitles or
load it directly from url loadsubs.net
Rule #1:
Make sure you know everything
about those you visit.
2: Never spend
more than 10 minutes.
Every extra minute increases the chance
of someone returning home unexpectedly.
3: Do not leave any DNA traces.
4: Don't waste time getting
an expensive reproduction.
Even a simple forgery will
go unnoticed for weeks.
5: Sooner or later,
one of two things will happen.
You find a work of art so valuable
that you never need to worry again...
Or...
you'll get caught.
HEADHUNTERS
Subtitles & Sync By
FridayToker
My name is Roger Brown.
"I'm 5'6" tall.
You don't need a Ph.D to realize
that I overcompensate for my height.
For instance,
my house is worth 30 million kroner.
I don't like it
and I can't afford it. But she...
Of course you have to come!
She loves it.
How often does one
of your girlfriends open a gallery?
I told her
I had inherited the money.
I had to give her
some kind of explanation.
But all I've inherited is bad genes.
We've gone through a long and intricate
process to reach the truth in this case.
For someone like me to get what he
wants, only one thing matters...
Money.
Go ahead, open it.
Lots of money.
But there is one thing
Diana wants more than anything else.
And that is exactly the one thing
I do not want to give her.
- Isn't she cute?
- Real cute.
You see, Diana Strum-Eiiassen is
one of those tall, smart beauties.
Hi, guys! The large paintings go
to the back, okay?
The type used to being loved.
The type who take love for granted.
And there are plenty of men
who would love her.
"Men taller than 5'6 ".
But soon my time will come.
My opportunity. I can feel it.
In the meantime,
I play for high stakes.
If you don't gamble, you don't win.
What are your plans
for tomorrow?
- Why?
- We have a dinner invitation.
We're invited to dinner.
We are invited to dinner?
Yes. There's someone
I want you to meet.
Are you telling
others about us, Lotte?
There's just someone
I'd like you to meet.
This ends right here and now.
I'm really sorry about it.
- Please don't.
- No no no, Lotte!
- We don't exist.
- Please stop.
An impressive resumé
you've got here, Lander.
Thank you. Yes, I believe
I'm the right man for Pathfinder.
I would like to hear a bit about
your life outside the job as well.
Is there such a thing?
So you live here in Oslo?
And are married to? Thank you, Oda.
Camilla.
We've been married for nine years.
- Two kids. They are in school.
- Does she hold a job?
Yes. At a downtown law firm.
Nine-to-five, every day?
Who stays home if the children fall ill?
She does, of course.
So there's no maid
at home during the day?
- No.
- Dog?
- Do we have a dog? No.
- No? Allergic?
No.
How much would you consider that your
reputation as a leader is worth, Lander?
My... reputation?
What do you mean?
This work is by Julian Opie
and is worth a quarter of a million.
Do you own any art
in the same price range?
Actually, yes.
A Munch lithograph.
"The Brooch."
Could you estimate
its value just by looking at it?
- Well, I'm not sure.
- You're not sure.
This one, for instance,
consists of a few circles and lines.
The coloration is monotone
and without texture.
The only thing...
I repeat, the only thing...
that makes this work worth
a quarter of a million
is the artist's reputation.
And your point is
the same thing goes for leaders?
Exactly.
Which is why
you will not take this job.
- What?
- My God. You applied for it yourself.
What else was I supposed to do?
You should have had
someone tip us off about it.
and then pretended you didn't know
about it when we got in touch.
But...
It's all a game, Lander.
Listen. Pathfinder's chairman
and finance manager
will be here tomorrow,
and I'd like you to meet them.
You're going to listen politely to them,
then you will explain
why you are no longer interested
- and wish them good luck.
- But I would not seem serious.
No. They will see you as ambitious,
as someone
who knows his own worth.
Lander...
- This is your opportunity.
- Opportunity?
Let me build your reputation
and I promise you a position which
quintuples your income within two years.
- Within two years?
- Within two years.
How can you promise this?
Because I have never given a client
a recommendation he hasn't followed.
- Never?
- Never.
But how?
The answer starts with an.
- Reputation?
- My entire career is based on it.
Hi.
- Yes?
- I set you up for the interview
with Jeremias Lander and Pathfinder
tomorrow at 12 o'clock.
- The information is in the file.
- Great.
But listen,
your wife is opening her gallery
this weekend, and I wondered...
could I attend?
- Are you invited?
- Exactly my question!
' Am I?
' Are you...,
I got an invoice of 357,000
for redecoration
in Kasper Hansen Street.
- Yes, that's correct.
- Well, what's that about?
I helped Diana with some expenses.
She opens her own gallery on Friday.
You have to start cutting down
on your expenses, Roger.
You may go bankrupt at any time.
I'm working on it, Frode.
I'm working on it.
As your accountant,
it's my duty to inform you
about the seriousness
of the situation.
You have overdrawn your account by several
hundred thousands for dinners...
There's a call coming in here.
I'll call you later.
We have a candidate.
Jeremias Lander, lives at Skoyen.
Okay. Got him. When?
He has a meeting at Alfa tomorrow at 12.
It will last one hour.
- Nobody home?
- No dog, no maid, wife works downtown.
See you in 20 minutes.
The fence in Gothenburg
demanded 50%.
Ove Kjikerud charged 20%
to disconnect alarms,
fetch the an' in my garage,
and bring it to Sweden by car.
To get him employed at Tripolis was
one of my smartest moves.
I myself was left' with 80,000.
80, 000.
Not even enough for my next
quarterly payment on my house.
Something had to be done.
- Nice to see you.
- Hi.
- Thanks for coming.
It's looking real good.
Not even half of the guests
have arrived yet.
But I don't have the time
to greet anyone either because...
Listen, it's going just fine.
- Congratulations. Fantastic exhibition.
- Thank you.
- Something crazy happened today.
- Like what?
I cannot tell you now,
but I want you to meet him.
Meet who?
So this is my husband, Roger Brown.
- Clas Greve.
- Nice to meet you.
Clas just moved here
from the Netherlands.
Excuse me.
Hi, are you on your way?
No, a few screaming kids
just liven up the party...
So what brings you
to Norway? Work?
No. I inherited
my grandmother's apartment.
- She was Norwegian?
- Yes.
And a few months ago,
I chose to go into early retirement.
So now I've moved here
- to redecorate the apartment.
- So you retired?
- Yes.
- From what?
I was the CEO
of a Dutch technology company.
I work with GPS sales.
Dutch?
Not HOTE, by any chance?
Yes, exactly.
Weren't they just bought up
by a large American company? Amtech?
- You are also in the business?
- No.
But why did you quit?
Isn't it exciting?
I won't bore you with job chatter.
I'm in the recruitment business.
You won't bore me with job chatter.
Are you familiar with Pathfinder?
Yes, of course.
They were our competitors.
Roger, I'm sorry, I have to go.
But enjoy the rest of your evening.
Clas! Pathfinder seeks a new manager.
Someone who can stand up
against foreign takeovers.
- How about a meeting?
- Sorry, Roger.
Then let's have lunch.
Monday at 12:00.
We could drop the job chatter
and talk about other things...
art, redecoration,
Polish handymen.
Could I have a pen?
I'll write down the restaurant's name.
You're not used
to being turned down?
A farewell present
for long and faithful service?
No, I stole it.
See you then.
Give my regards to your charming wife.
I will.
- This is my husband.
- Roger Brown. Nice to meet you.
- Brede Sperre, Kripos.
- Yes, we've seen you on TV.
He investigates
alt burglaries now.
I thought you investigated
murders.
Yes, but this is getting so big
that we sent in all our resources.
We're going to stop this now.
Are you in the alt business as well?
No, I work as a headhunter.
In the recruitment business, for Alfa.
I see. One of the partners.
What do you mean?
Well, I complimented your wife here
on her expensive earrings.
She said they were
a present from you.
Yes.
The best of us
get good bonus deals.
I wish we had those
in my line of work as well.
' Sperre...:
- Yes?
We're from VG.
Could we have a photo?
Of course.
Hi. How nice of you to come.
Roger? Are you coming?
Look at this.
"The Calydonian Boar Hunt,"
by Rubens.
It was stolen when the Germans looted
the gallery in Antwerp in 1941.
It's been missing ever since.
Do you know where it is now?
No.
In Clas Greve's apartment
in Oscar Street.
- What?
- Clas Greve's grandmother had
a secret love affair
with a German officer during the war.
But he was arrested
and shot a few days later.
She panicked, fearing someone
would discover the relationship.
And then she hid the painting?
- Yes, something of the sort.
- Oh well, but it's not genuine.
I don't think German officers
collected reproductions, Roger.
Well, why did he tell you about it?
He came by the gallery
to ask if I could evaluate it
or if I knew someone who could.
You're saying that
Clas Greve has a genuine Rubens
hanging in his apartment
in Oscar Street?
- Yes.
- Here in Oslo?
Yes. But I offered
to contact an alt museum
to have it moved as soon as possible.
Next week.
You don't place a painting
like this in a safe-deposit box.
How much do you think it's worth?
Tens of millions.
Maybe a hundred.
Do you know what I think?
I think we should celebrate.
Celebrate what?
That you opened your own gallery.
And the two of us.
Thanks for supporting me, Roger.
Everything is going to be fine.
What do you mean?
That you and I should
start thinking about the future.
- Ove here.
- We have a candidate.
Do you know what the time is?
His name is Clas Greve.
He lives in 25 Oscar Street.
What, he is grave?
No, his name is Greve.
Ove?
Ove, what's happening? Ove?
Sorry. Natasha is here.
Come again?
Meet me at the cabin tomorrow.
No, not tomorrow! It's Saturday.
I've got her for the whole weekend.
We want to do something nice.
Not tomorrow.
This is a big deal, Ove.
We only have a couple of days.
- One o'clock!
- Yes, okay.
- You are so sweet.
- Good morning.
- Listen.
- Yes?
What you said yesterday
about the future.
- Yes?
- Does it include the sound
of tiny feet
shuffling along these corridors?
- Maybe.
- Don't give me "maybe," Roger.
I told you yesterday
that everything will be fine,
- and it will.
- But I want that conversation now.
Definitely, but I have
an important meeting first.
- Do you think I'm stupid?
- Hmm?
- You have an important meeting?
- Yes.
A meeting that was
set up during the night?
I have to go.
I'll call you later.
- What are you so scared of?
- Nothing.
I'm scared of dogs
and you when you are like this.
Don't just make jokes about it.
If you want us to be childless
the rest of our lives,
I would really like to know.
Didn't you hear me?
We'll have the conversation,
but not now because I have
an important meeting.
I've tried to talk about this
for seven years, Roger.
And it will take another seven years
if you keep nagging this way.
I didn't mean that.
You will never give me a child.
So... how many millions
are we talking about?
Maybe up to a hundred.
A hundred?
- This happens every time, Ove.
- Eh?
I've told you I don't like
those things lying around.
Don't start again.
You know I always carry weapons.
At home,
I've got weapons everywhere.
Got a gun
within reach in every room.
You should get one as well.
Sooner or later they'll be coming.
We do it this way:
You go to Gothenburg
and get a reproduction.
There are many available,
but we need a good one.
I have lunch with Clas Greve on Monday.
Then I will get...
Ove?
Women.
Like I tried to say before I was
interrupted by a Russian prostitute,
I have lunch with Greve on Monday.
I'll find out then
when the apartment is empty,
so that I can fetch the painting.
You go to Sweden immediately. Now.
Okay. No, shit, I can't.
- What?
- I'm busy.
- Busy?
- Natasha is here.
I'm making a film with her
before she goes back.
Film?
I've arranged everything
with the guys at work.
- They've changed shifts and everything.
- You're filming her?
It's such a long time between her
visits, so I need something to watch.
I just activate the alarm,
and the cameras start rolling.
- She doesn't know you're filming her?
- No way.
And the Tripolis guards?
They are watching the two of you?
The cameras are not directed
towards the bed!
What do you take me for?
They see her undress
and a bit of fingering.
She's cut her hair. Looks nice.
The rest is private. Cool, eh?
The painting will be removed from
the apartment in just a few days, Ove.
Do you realize how big this is?
She is here twice in six months.
You'll be left with millions.
With that kind of money
you can buy her.
For the rest of your life.
I'll have one without scampi jelly,
and dressing on the side.
As you wish. Thank you.
Will you settle in Oslo now
or will you do a lot of commuting?
Three and a half million,
plus stock options.
I'm afraid you take things
for granted, Greve.
Don't forget you're a foreigner.
Norwegian companies would like...
Roger. I don't doubt that your methods
will work on most people.
And I respect that, of course.
But we have both been
in this situation before.
- You practically dribbled over me on...
- Dribbled?
You drooled when we met at the gallery,
and with good reason.
On that occasion, the problem
was not that I was a foreigner,
but that I was not interested in a job.
But you get to reflect a lot
during a weekend, and I concluded
that redecoration is not
that interesting in the long run.
So if it's okay with you,
why don't we simply drop the charade?
I surrender.
But I still need more data on you.
- For my client.
- Do you play squash?
Are you married?
- Divorced.
- Children?
- Unfortunately not.
- Dog?
Yes.
I've got one.
He is in Amsterdam.
- In quarantine?
- I'll fly down to get him tomorrow.
The GPS business is a tough one?
- Your back.
- Oh.
- That's from the army.
- The army?
I enrolled when I was 18.
After a few years I was enlisted
in an elite unit which specialized...
- Specialized in what?
- Tracking.
- Tracking of?
- People.
Missing people, fugitives.
And the technology
came from HOTE?
Exactly.
They produced
microscopic transmitters.
I had some ideas for improvements,
so they recruited me.
Where did you get those scars?
Bolivia.
And how?
Were you tortured or what?
No, I was lucky.
I got out in time.
Sounds like something from a film.
Believe me, Roger.
You've never seen this on film.
When do you think we can arrange
a meeting with Pathfinder?
Any time.
When are you back from Amsterdam?
- The day after tomorrow.
- Let's do it then.
Diana?
Out with customers Back late.
No, Murphy. Come here.
Hit the ring, hit the ring!
Hit the one you want,
hit the one you love.
Hi, this is Diana.
I can't answer the phone right now,
but you know what to do
after the beep. Have a nice day.
- Hi.
- You're so late.
- I tried to call your cellphone.
Right. I can't find it.
I must have left it at the gallery.
Was there anything urgent?
No.
I just wanted to hear your voice.
That's sweet.
Come and sit down.
This film just started.
No.
I'm beat.
I'm going to bed.
We developed this jelly containing
hundreds of transmitters per milliliter.
It adheres to all materials.
It's invisible
and just about impossible to remove.
- You mean Trace.
- Exactly.
The disadvantage is that Trace
is hypersensitive to dirt and mud.
And my personal experience as a soldier
is that when you're stuck in,
pardon my French,
the asshole of the world,
you are dependent
on your equipment.
Being introduced by Brown
is obviously of great significance.
In the final stage, he has to
give us his recommendations.
Excuse me for a moment.
Great meeting.
Thanks a lot.
- Really good.
- Thank you so much.
- Take care.
- Thank you.
When will you write
the recommendation?
- We have to make a decision first.
- What was that?
Nothing is decided.
There are other candidates.
We have to consider the total picture.
We will get back to you.
Damn it, Roger,
did we attend the same meeting?
It couldn't have been better.
They were ready
to sign the contract on the spot.
Well, then your chances are good.
- Hi.
- Shit, are you calling on a cellphone?
- You're going to Gothenburg tonight.
- What? Tonight?
The painting has to be traded
for money, as quickly as possible.
- Hi.
I have to talk to you.
You can't look me up this way, Lotte.
Please, just give me two seconds.
I'm sorry if it's my fault
you're feeling this way.
There's really nothing more
to talk about.
Nothing at all.
Do you need money?
I miss you.
- I miss you so much.
- Lotte.
Lotte.
Don't contact me again.
You look tired.
Thank you.
Anything wrong?
No.
- A lot to do at work?
- Quite a bit.
I had a meeting today with Pathfinder.
And Clas Greve.
- Did it work out fine?
- No.
- He won't get the job?
- Definitely not.
When I get to the office tomorrow,
I'll call all the other agencies
and make sure
he won't get a single job in Norway.
Why is that?
- By the way, did you find your phone?
- Pardon?
Your cellphone.
You said you lost your cellphone.
- Yes, I did.
- Was it in the gallery or what?
- Yes.
- That's great.
- Some more wine?
- Yes. Thank you.
Ove?
Come here.
Hi.
- Hi.
- What are you doing here?
I saw you go down here,
and you didn't come out.
- I got a bit worried.
- About what?
Nothing.
- Roger.
- Yes.
Have a nice day at work.
I love you.
Ove? Ove?
- Ove, where do you live?
- Nathas...
- Not Natasha. Where do you live? Ove?
Ove? Ove?
Ove? Where do you live?
Ove, what happened in the garage?
Did you see anyone?
Ove, answer me. Ove?
Did you see what happened?
Was there anyone there?
Listen!
Was there anyone there, Ove?
Was there?
What the hell is going on here?
Shit, what's going on?
- Ove, what's the password?
- Eh?
What's the password?
- What's the password for the alarm?
- Nata...
We have to deactivate the alarm.
What's the password?
- Nata...
- Stop going on about her!
- What's the password?
- That's what I'm saying. Natasha!
With "sh" or "sch"?
Ove, "sh" or "sch"?
Ove?
Ove? How is it going?
Ove, how are you doing?
- What happened?
- You sat on a syringe in my car.
A syringe?
- Relax. You were lucky.
- Lucky?!
It must have hit your knee, so that
you didn't absorb all the poison.
- You didn't expose us?
- No way.
- Did you fuck up?
- That's not what this is about!
- You didn't fuck up, did you?
- Diana is having an affair with Clas.
He wouldn't kill you
just because he fucks your wife!
- Call 911!
- We don't want the police here!
Please, Roger.
I need to get to a hospital,
or else I'll die.
- I'll get you some milk.
- Eh?
Milk neutralizes poison. That's what
they would do at the hospital.
Then give me milk!
- Call them.
- Don't do anything stupid, Ove.
Then I'll do it myself.
Just calm down now.
Roger! I would like
to talk to you.
No!
' Roger?
Our main research interest
was the tracking of people.
Microscopic transmitters.
Hello. I just thought
I'd visit the cabin.
I thought you were Kjikerud.
- No.
- It's his car.
Yes.
Aren't you some kind
of businessman?
I was fired.
May I park the car inside the barn?
- 500 per 24 hours.
- 500?
You could park for free
by the roadside, you know.
If you touch the tractor,
I want compensation!
What a rush of people here today!
- I'm just visiting Roger Brown.
- You mean that businessman?
Yes.
- What do you want from him?
- We have an appointment.
What you're all doing up there
is none of my business,
but he probably didn't invite you
for coffee and cakes in the cabin.
In the cabin?
Yes, and since it's my property,
maybe a slight compensation
would be fair?
Search!
Hello?
Who are you?
Oh shit.
You're not supposed
to be out of bed.
- Did anyone ask for me?
- No.
Get back to bed.
Well, except for the police.
- Huh?
- They're waiting in the corridor.
I told them you should
have your breakfast first.
Because if you manage to smash
the larynx, you're a good fighter.
Experienced. Ever heard
about something called ko-daw-ying?
No wonder. Do you know
how many martial arts there are?
Three thousand. Three thousand.
You've got wushu,
martial arts from China.
Tahtib, Egyptian stick fighting.
That's him! That's him.
He's running away!
Hey! Hey!
Freeze! Freeze!
Sunded, I've got him!
Hi. My name is Olav Sunded,
from Kripos.
You are a suspect in the murder
of the farmer Sindre Aa.
Come with us, Kjikerud, and we'll go
through the rest at the station.
What?
You are Ove Kjikerud?
Yes.
Where are we going?
We're going to Elverum Police Station,
for questioning.
And I hope you cooperate, so that
I can go back home to Oslo tomorrow.
Attention all patrol cars.
In other words, both of them.
Bravo 3-0 here.
Egmon Karisen has reported
his truck stolen.
Did Karisen sound sober? Over.
Not exactly. Over.
Call Bamse Pub.
It's probably parked there. Over.
Maybe it's parked behind Kiwi.
Why did you kill
the farmer, Kjikerud?
I have no idea
what you're talking about.
Don't even try.
Your Mercedes was parked
in Sindre Aa's barn,
and you drove
his tractor into a ditch.
- I've never heard that name.
- We have several witnesses who saw...
There is no truck
parked outside Bamse Pub.
No, but I've got
more urgent matters now. Over and out.
- But, Kjikerud...
- Maybe you could check behind Kiwi.
- We have several witnesses who...
- Damn, there it is!
Brugd here. Call Egmon.
I can see his truck now.
Probably his son stole it again. Over.
What are you doing, Brugd?
Well, like I said, Kjikerud,
we have plenty of evidence,
and still you deny everything.
So start feeding me details,
because you lost me completely.
Aa's neighbour found you
in the ditch beside the tractor.
We developed this jelly containing
hundreds of transmitters per milliliter.
It adheres to all materials.
Its invisible,
and just about impossible to remove.
I love you.
You just sit there repeating
the same thing over and over again.
- We have to get out.
- No, we don't have to get out.
- He's going to kill us all.
- Relax, Kjikerud.
He has rubbed
transmitters into my hair!
- Do you realize what you're saying?
- We have to get out!
- Calm down.
- He wants to kill me!
He rubbed transmitters into my hair!
We have to get out!
- He's going to kill me!
- Calm down!
- We have to get out!
- No, we don't have to get out.
Hi, this is Diana.
Hello? Hello?
Roger? Is that you?
After finishing here,
we go to Forensic.
- Yes.
- And then we'll have
a look at Kjikerud's house.
Eh?
"Hi, I'm a single girl from Gjovik."
I think you are Norway's
most sexy policeman, and the best.
"Would you like to meet me?
I agree to just about anything."
What the hell happened here?
Lotte, wait. Wait.
- What are you doing here?
- Please let me in.
- What happened to you?
- I need help. Please.
Thank you.
I don't mean to involve you in this.
In what?
When they ask, don't lie.
Just tell them I was here.
Tell them I forced my way in.
What happened?
Wait here, okay?
I'll get something to clean it with.
Have you got a pair of scissors?
Lotte, who are you contacting?
- Give me that phone!
- Ow!
- Stop it. Stop.
"Roger is alive.
He is in my apartment now."
It's not what you think!
- What's happening?
- I don't know!
- Answer me! Answer me!
- No, I don't know. I don't know.
- What's happening?
- It's not my fault!
What's going on?
- Please.
- What does Greve want from me?
- It's the Pathfinder job.
- You don't kill people for a job!
It's about billions, okay?
They've been working on this for months,
ever since they found out that.
- Pathfinder is looking for a new CEO.
- Who are they?
- Who are "they"?!
- Clas.
He still works for HOTE.
What?
- What?
- They have massive economic problems.
Amtech can save them.
They demand that HOTE provide them
with Pathfinders' technology.
- This was Clas' assignment.
- Are you all insane?
I was to get to know you,
then introduce you to him.
But he found a new plan, when you
suddenly didn't want to see me any more.
- What plan?
- He had to find a way to meet you.
His grandmother had an old reproduction
of a Rubens painting.
So he made up a wild story
that she had gotten it
from a German officer during the war.
He looked up Diana and told her
the story, and she believed him.
Then he met you.
The only thing I've done
is rub transmitters into your hair.
Did you do that?
Did you smear
that shit into my hair?
- Diana?
- Huh?
- Is Diana involved in this?
- I don't know, but I think so.
- You think so?
- It's not my fault!
I didn't want this to happen!
I just want to get away from him.
Please help me.
May I have a glass of water?
Lotte! Lotte!
The suspect in the farmer murder case
died in the accident,
with three of the four
police officers.
The last police officer
is still missing.
Military divers are now searching
in and along the river at the site.
Now to the Middle East, where...
Diana.
Roger?
What happened?
Are you okay?
Don't look at me that way.
I know why you left.
There's nothing more
between Clas and me now. I promise.
I tried to tell you in the garage,
but I couldn't.
- And then you just disappeared.
- Diana, what do you know
- about everything that happened?
- No, I have to tell you this now.
I didn't want it to happen,
but you hurt me,
he was so easy to talk to
and I couldn't stand it any more.
It was wrong, and I'm so ashamed.
Because you are the one I want.
If you really think we shouldn't
have children, we don't need to.
I'm willing to do anything.
You really do love me.
You must never doubt that.
Promise me.
And you didn't know anything?
- About what?
- You didn't know anything.
Oh my God.
What has happened?
Come here.
Dog bites are very serious, Roger.
You have to see a doctor.
It's not that convenient right now.
Hold this.
What are you planning to do now?
I don't know.
They'll soon find out
who died in the accident.
I have to remove evidence.
And then?
I have to get away from here.
Make a new start.
Maybe we...
maybe you and I could...
I can wait awhile
before I report it stolen.
I have to clean these too.
Did you love her?
No.
How could you be
so god damn stupid? Eh?
Steal works of art?
To buy things I don't need?
Who do you think I am?
You had asked me
what I'm scared of.
And I've been scared
since I first met you.
I've been scared
that you would leave me.
Scared that we would have a child
which you would love more than me.
And I've been scared that you would
see me as I really am
and hate it.
I need to see you.
Diana
I'm sorry about this, Greve.
It's quite all right.
Roger Brown is on an unexpected
journey abroad, you see.
That sounds exciting.
Yes, he had to save
an important contract.
But you are in safe hands now.
There are only formalities left,
so it won't take very long.
Hi, we are supposed
to change a fan in B4.
- Yes.
- We've been in and out the whole day,
but this card doesn't work.
Yes, but just wait
until the other guy comes back.
Who then?
PATHOLOGY DEPARTMENT.
AUTOPSY.
Thank you.
Hello, guys.
- Hi.
- Sorry, but we're a bit behind here.
A lady just got in who's been lying dead
on heating cables for two weeks.
Have you got any thoughts on this?
Typical car accident injuries
on both of them.
The cause of death
is internal hemorrhages.
But where are the peanuts?
It says here there was
a bag of peanuts. Where is it?
I certainly didn't eat them, Sperre.
Has anyone been in here?
Anyone unauthorized?
To steal a bag of peanuts?
Who's that?
What the hell is
going on here, Roger?
Are you removing evidence?
Do you think
you can get away with this?
What the hell?
So you realized
that stuff about the hair?
That it's where
the transmitters were?
Lotte placed them there.
- That's why you killed her?
- Does it feel like a loss?
- I'll give you a choice.
- That Lotte died?
If you tell me
what the hell is going on,
I'll shoot you in the head.
If not, you'll get
a bullet in your stomach.
Don't you have
any feelings regarding this?
Why do you want to know?
Because I would like to know
if people like you really exist.
- People like me?
- Yes.
People who are not capable of love.
People without empathy.
- Empathy?
- Yes.
If you want the answer,
just look at yourself in the mirror.
- No.
- Yes.
- I'm not like you.
- You're not?
No.
I have loved someone.
You have loved someone?
Diana?
You have loved her?
I'm afraid I have bad news for you.
She tells me she longs for me.
She wants me.
And I'm only human.
Have you ever loved anyone?
Except for your dead dog?
I have no time for this, Roger.
I've got an appointment
with Diana tonight.
You fetched the hair.
You knew I'd be coming for you. Why?
A shot in the stomach
means a slow death.
You'll beg me to kill you.
So I ask you for the last time:
Why am I here?
What are you smiling at?
Hold it right there!
What happened now?
He was shot! What happened?
Do you know why I was smiling, Clas?
Because you just proved
that Diana loves me.
She didn't come to you
because she wanted you.
She came to you
to put cartridges in your pistol.
She replaced
the cartridge in your pistol
with an empty cartridge.
Or what do you call them
in Danish? Blanks?
What are you talking about?
She hates you.
She wants you to die.
But I will give you one chance.
I have no idea how many bullets
Diana managed to switch.
This is not like you, Clas.
Is it over?
Yes.
I may not know myself I
but I know others.
And that's what I gambled on.
Welcome to this press conference,
arranged by Oslo Police District
and Kripos.
I had prepared well.
The pistol I took
from the crash site
would be found by the police
on Kjikerud's bed table...
the same pistol
that killed Lotte Madsen,
whom the press presented
as Greve's lover.
How the "art burglars"
Ove Kjikerud and Clas Greve
killed each other
in a bloody shootout...
The alarm has gone off
over at Ove's place.
Was watched
by the whole world on the Internet.
The police would also find
that the pistol Greve fired
matched the one which fired
the bullet that penetrated Ove's head.
He should never
have picked up that pistol.
We are pleased to present
a breakthrough in the case.
But even though
I had done everything right,
there was one thing
I could not change.
Ove was already dead
when I shot Greve.
But Brede Sperre is
Norway's most renowned investigator.
Leaving cases unsolved
is not his style.
Especially not after
VG called him:
"The man who makes
Norway sleep well at night."
Because he is competent?
Obviously.
But mainly because he has realized what
it takes to get ahead in this world.
And what would that be?
Like I mentioned, this has been
a long, complicated investigation.
The answer starts with an "R."
Reputation.
Something that gets you
TV exposure,
and provides you with texts
from unknown women.
We believe
they celebrated the theft
and that they lost control completely.
Because they end up torturing a dog
and killing the farmer
who owns the cabin?
That's correct.
REALTOR OPEN HOUSE
Have a nice day. Both of you.
We are ready here, Roger.
Send in the candidate
in one minute.
- Yes.
- Ferdinand.
Thank you.
Hi. I'm sorry.
Please sit down.
I asked you to come here because
I think we are at the end of a long,
and as you know, dramatic hunt
for Pathfinder's new leader.
In the last round,
it was completely unrealistic
to have him released
from his present position.
Without promising too much,
I believe I have persuaded him.
Please welcome.
Jeremias Lander.
Nice to see you again.
My name is Roger Brown.
"I'm 5'6 " tall.
And you know what?
That's more than enough.
HEADHUNTERS